Finding Aid for Michigan Association for Health, Physical Education, Recreation, and Dance records, 1946-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- President's Files 1967-
  - 1967-1989
    - Division of Girls and Women's Sports (DGWS) 1972-1974 (Box 9)
    - Editor's Reports 1971-1974 (Box 9)
    - Executive Secretary's Reports 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Fact Sheets undated (Box 9)
    - Financial Policy 1971 (Box 9)
    - Financial Reports 1971-1982 (Box 9)
    - Health Education Division 1972-1982 (Box 9)
    - Historical Committee 1971-1987 (Box 9)
    - Honor Award Committee 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - Interaction Workshop on Performance Objectives 1973 (Box 9)
    - Leadership Conference at Gull Lake 1974 (Box 9)
    - Leadership Workshop 1971-1989 (Box 9)
    - Legislative Committee 1972 (Box 9)
    - Membership Committee 1971-1982 (Box 9)
    - Midwest District Representative Reports 1965-1982 (Box 9)
    - Nominating Committee 1972-1982 (Box 9)
    - Operating Codes 1968-1972 (Box 9)
    - Past President's Committee 1985-1989 (Box 9)
    - Performance Objectives Project 1974 (Box 9)
    - Physical Education Guidelines 1974 (Box 9)
    - Physical Education Public Information Project (PEPI) 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - President's Club 1981 (Box 9)
    - Presidents' Reports to Representative Assembly 1967-1974 (Box 9)
    - Professional Development Division Report 1982 (Box 9)
    - Program Planning Suggestions (Box 9)
    - "Report of Examination of Financial Statement," 1973 (Box 9)
    - Reports to Representative Assembly 1971-1982 (Box 9)
    - Resolutions Committee 1972 (Box 9)
    - Standing Committees 1971-1973 (Box 9)
    - Task Force on Competency-Based Teacher Education 1974 (Box 9)
  - William Podoll
    - Constitution (Box 15)
    - Convention 1981 (Box 15)
    - Dance for Heart (Box 15)
    - Jump Rope for Heart, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Leadership Meeting (Box 15)
    - Operating Codes (Box 15)
    - Save a Sweetheart Dance (Box 15)
    - Working files 1981 (formerly in binder) (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Gloria Neve 1988-1992
    - MAHPERD 1988-1992, chiefly 1991, 1 blue binder
      - Constitution (Box 18)
      - Codes-Executives (Box 18)
      - Codes-Divisions (Box 18)
      - Codes-Committees (Box 18)
      - Codes-Other (Box 18)
      - Roster (Box 18)
      - Minutes (Box 18)
      - Treasurer/Budget (Box 18)
      - Letters (Box 18)
      - Special (Box 18)
      - Awards (Box 18)
      - Midwest (Box 18)
    - MAHPERD 1990-1997 chiefly 1992, 1 black binder
      - Constitution (Box 18)
      - Roster (Box 18)
      - Minutes (Box 18)
      - Treasurer/Budget (Box 18)
      - Letters (Box 18)
      - MIS (Box 18)
      - Applied Strategic Planning (Box 18)
    - Loose material removed from MAHPERD 1991-1992, 2 folders; 1 blue binder (Box 18)
    - Loose material removed from MAHPERD 1991-1992, 1 black binder (Box 18)
- Yearly Files
  Yearly Files, which comprises 1.25 linear feet of the collection, consists of memoranda, correspondence, meeting minutes, agendas, schedules, rosters, progress reports, budget proposals, financial reports, and service and project descriptions. The majority of the records are created by the administrative officers and the MAHPERD departmental representatives. There are also documents created by agencies outside MAHPERD, including AAHPERD, Michigan Department of Education, Michigan Recreation and Park Association, American Heart Association, National Association for Sport and Physical Recreation, and regional universities. The materials in this series document the perpetual process of improving the health of the community through improving physical education instruction and evaluation.
  - 1961-1965, 1972-1975, 1977-1984, 14 folders (Box 9)
  - 1985-1993, 12 folders (Box 10)
- Executive director files
  - 1987-1991/1992 (Box 12)
  - 1991/1992 (cont.)-1994 (Box 13)
  - 1994 (cont.)-2000 (Box 14)
- Honor Awards & Past President's Files
  - Honor Award Recipients Directory (Box 16)
  - Honor Award Recipients
    - Blanchard, Vaughn 1957 (Box 16)
    - Mitchell, Elmer 1957 (Box 16)
    - Hussey, Delia 1958 (Box 16)
    - Boughner, Ruth 1959 (Box 16)
    - Campbell, Laurie 1959 (Box 16)
    - Murray, Ruth 1959 (Box 16)
    - Finlayson, Ann 1960 (Box 16)
    - Olds, Lloyd 1960 (Box 16)
    - Forsythe, Charles E. 1961 (Box 16)
    - Harris, Augusta 1961 (Box 16)
    - Hollway, Lou 1961 (Box 16)
    - Smith, Julian 1961 (Box 16)
    - Roell, Candace 1962 (Box 16)
    - Williams, Louise 1964 (Box 16)
    - Thompson, Howard 1964 (Box 16)
    - Cavanaugh, Patric 1966 (Box 16)
    - Hunsicker, Paul 1966 (Box 16)
    - Burton, Margaret 1968 (Box 16)
    - McNamara, Jane 1968 (Box 16)
    - Hartzler, Genevieve 1969 (Box 16)
    - Thomas, Alfred 1969 (Box 16)
    - Meyers, Frank 1972 (Box 16)
    - Zenti, Rico 1972 (Box 16)
    - Koenig, Francis 1973 (Box 16)
    - Large, Margaret 1973 (Box 16)
    - Wessel, Janet 1973 (Box 16)
    - Steig, Peggy 1974 (Box 16)
    - Jones, Tom R. 1975 (Box 16)
    - Galetti, Steve 1976 (Box 16)
    - Menzi, Betty 1976 (Box 16)
    - Duff, Char 1977 (Box 16)
    - Johnson, Jack 1977 (Box 16)
    - Dornbos, Sanford "Bud" 1978 (Box 16)
    - Ocker, Phyllis 1978 (Box 16)
    - Clark, Marilyn 1979 (Box 16)
    - Gans, Marvin 1979 (Box 16)
    - Galetti, Jeannine 1980 (Box 16)
    - Luby, Robert 1980 (Box 16)
    - Blamer, William C. 1981 (Box 16)
    - Zirulnik, Ann 1981 (Box 16)
    - Denman, Charlotte 1982 (Box 16)
    - Kowalk, Clayton 1982 (Box 16)
    - McCormick, George 1982 (Box 16)
    - Ellis, Kathryn 1983 (Box 16)
    - Bensley, Loren 1984 (Box 16)
    - Niemeyer, Roy K. 1984 (Box 16)
    - Kilpatrick, William 1985 (Box 16)
    - Jubb, Wanda 1985 (Box 16)
    - Assenmacher, Stephen 1986 (Box 16)
    - Seefeldt, Vern 1986 (Box 16)
    - Signor, Joyce 1986 (Box 16)
    - Haubenstricker, John 1987 (Box 16)
    - Ray, Hal 1988 (Box 16)
    - Treadway, Jean 1988 (Box 16)
    - Vogel, Paul 1989 (Box 16)
    - Willoughby, Robert 1989 (Box 16)
    - Pedersen, Erik 1990 (Box 16)
    - Reuschlein, Sam 1991 (Box 16)
    - Meyer, Ruth Ann 1992 (Box 16)
    - Curry, Doug 1993 (Box 16)
    - Neve, Gloria D. 1994 (Box 16)
    - Kolp, Susan J. 1995 (Box 16)
    - Krause, Joyce 1996 (Box 16)
    - Kuntzleman, Charles 1997 (Box 16)
    - DeVore, Linda 1998 (Box 16)
    - DeBruyn, Maxine 1999 (Box 16)
    - Price, Fred 2000 (Box 16)
    - Hensey, Donna 2001 (Box 16)
    - Laughna, Beverly 2002 (Box 16)
    - Rowe, Patricia 2003 (Box 16)
    - Catherman, Dave 2004 (Box 16)
    - DeJong, Glenna (Box 16)
    - Berkey, Debra (Box 16)
    - Paciorek, Michael (Box 16)
  - Past Presidents Directory (Box 16)
  - Honor Award Recipients & Past Presidents (Box 16)
  - Past Presidents
    - Bowen, Wilbur P. 1927 (Box 16)
    - Murray, Ruth 1933 (Box 16)
    - Finlayson, Anne 1943 (Box 16)
    - Roell, Candace 1945 (Box 16)
    - Fink, Jane 1959 (Box 16)
    - Thompson, Howard 1960 (Box 16)
    - Cavanaugh, Patric 1962 (Box 16)
    - Hartzler, Genevieve 1967 (Box 16)
    - Niemeyer, Roy K. 1968 (Box 16)
    - Duff, Charlotte A. 1969 (Box 16)
    - Dornbos, Sanford "Bud" 1970 (Box 16)
    - Meyer, Ruth Ann 1971 (Box 16)
    - Jones, Tom R. 1972 (Box 16)
    - Menzi, Betty 1973 (Box 16)
    - Ocker, Phyllis 1975 (Box 16)
    - Gans, Marvin 1976 (Box 16)
    - Blamer, William 1978 (Box 16)
    - Hixson, Chalmer 1979 (Box 16)
    - Podoll, William 1981 (Box 16)
    - Kilpatrick, William 1980 (Box 16)
    - Luby, Robert L. 1982 (Box 16)
    - Adams, Dick 1983 (Box 16)
    - Haubenstricker, John 1984 (Box 16)
    - Ray, Hal 1985 (Box 16)
    - Strumbel, Carolyne 1986 (Box 16)
    - Pedersen, Erik 1987 (Box 16)
    - Tice, Joyce 1988-1989 (Box 16)
    - Curry, Doug 1990 (Box 16)
    - Neve, Gloria D. 1991 (Box 16)
    - Wegener, Larry 1992 (Box 16)
    - Krause, Joyce 1993 (Box 16)
    - Cool, Ray 1994 (Box 16)
    - Miller, Ruth 1995 (Box 16)
    - Wolcott, Brian 1996 (Box 16)
    - Satterwhite, Norene 1997 (Box 16)
    - Paciorek, Michael 1998 (Box 16)
    - Holley-Foster, Victoria 1999 (Box 16)
    - Johnson, Tom 2000 (Box 16)
    - VanVolkinburg, Pat 2001 (Box 16)
    - Nottingham, Su 2002 (Box 16)
    - Rae, Sally 2003 (Box 16)
    - Rickens, Mary Ann 2004 (Box 16)
- Operation Pride Award and Teacher/Educator of the Year Award Recipients
  - Operation Pride Award Files (Box 17)
  - Historical Records Committee's Most Wanted [binder] (Box 17)
  - Honor Award Recipients File 2002 [binder] (Box 17)
  - Operation Pride Award Recipients and Teacher/Educator of the Year Recipients [binder] (Box 17)
  - Award Recipients
    - Corbett, Diane 1975 (Box 17)
    - Wonnacott, Anna 1990 (Box 17)
  - Toy, Teacher of the Year Award (Box 17)
  - Teacher of the Year Award Recipients
    - Lauer, Valerie 1991 (Box 17)
    - Charon, Carl 1991 (Box 17)
    - McGannon, Carolyn 1992 (Box 17)
    - Sipes, Victor 1994 (Box 17)
    - Northrup-Ryan, Cheri 1994 (Box 17)
    - Cooper, Martha 1994 (Box 17)
    - Holley, Victoria 1994 (Box 17)
    - Coquillard, Michael 1995 (Box 17)
    - Laughna, Beverly 1997 (Box 17)
    - Masi, Brian 1997 (Box 17)
    - Wollace, Lynde 1997 (Box 17)
    - Crane, Brenda 1998 (Box 17)
    - LeMerise, Mike 1998 (Box 17)
    - Rayl, Beth 1998 (Box 17)
    - Camp, Trudy 1998 (Box 17)
    - Post, Beth 1998 (Box 17)
    - Fields-Anderson, Portia 1998 (Box 17)
    - Lewis, Michael 1999 (Box 17)
    - Nash, John 1999 (Box 17)
    - Potter, Dave 1999 (Box 17)
    - Craven, Al 1999 (Box 17)
    - Sprecher, Karen 1994 (Box 17)
    - Mitchell, Louis 1999 (Box 17)
    - Brummer, Mary 2000 (Box 17)
    - Moinet, Debra 2000 (Box 17)
    - Dorato, Lisa 2000 (Box 17)
    - Nothingham, Su 2000 (Box 17)
    - Bousquet, Candice 2000 (Box 17)
    - Sipos-Roe, Deborah 2000 (Box 17)
    - Hogg, Daniel 2001 (Box 17)
    - Banagis, Steve 2001 (Box 17)
    - Gibson-Marshall, Kristy 2001 (Box 17)
    - Roberts, Peter A. 2001 (Box 17)
    - Sheffer, Kelly 2001 (Box 17)
    - Teare, Carla 2002 (Box 17)
    - Carolan, Kirk 2002 (Box 17)
    - Lake, Chris 2002 (Box 17)
    - Waryas, Kam 2002 (Box 17)
    - Gulick, Beth 2002 (Box 17)
    - Pedersen, Kirk 2002 & 2005 (Box 17)
    - Townsend, Rachael 2002 (Box 17)
    - Frauenknecht, Marianne 2002 (Box 17)
    - Rickens, Mary Ann 2003 (Box 17)
    - Sebesta, Kimberly 2003 (Box 17)
    - Milke, Mary Frances 2003 (Box 17)
    - Kip, Joanne 2003 (Box 17)
    - Kahl, Marilyn 2003 (Box 17)
    - LaNew, Jacquelyn 2003 (Box 17)
    - Rodriguez, Steve 2003 (Box 17)
    - Tomlinson, Amy 2003 (Box 17)
    - VanVolkinburg, Pat 2003 (Box 17)
    - Cooley, Bob 2004 (Box 17)
    - Gulick, Alan 2004 (Box 17)
    - Aman, Luther 2004 (Box 17)
    - Pittenger, Tammy 2004 (Box 17)
    - Wilson, Cindy 2004 (Box 17)
    - Caie, Michelle 2004 (Box 17)
    - Woods, Ranae 2005 (Box 17)
    - Jackson, Jamie 2005 (Box 17)
    - Tilt, Barbara 2005 (Box 17)
    - Hebert, Heidi 2005 (Box 17)
    - Adams, Elizabeth 2005 (Box 17)
    - Titsworth, Melissa 2005 (Box 17)
    - Fahlman, Mariane 2005 (Box 17)